Sergei Garin



job@garin.dev



linkedin.com/in/mrflashaccount



+31629040081



https://github.com/MrFlashAccount

Summary

Result-oriented frontend developer with experience in building performant, maintainable web applications. I have experience building rich SPAs with charts, complex logic, native-like UX, and performance-oriented ecommerce websites.

I love to speak the same language as UX Designers, so I love to create Design systems and UI kits focusing on UX, a11y, and composability.

I don't discriminate against anyone by race, religion, color, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, age, marital status, or disability status

Experience

Senior Frontend Developer

Cube

Feb 2022 - Apr 2023 (1 year 3 months)

Key responsibilities:

- Built from scratch CI/CD for the ui-kit (https://github.com/cube-js/cube-ui-kit). Steps includes:
- a) Run: unit and screenshot tests, typecheck, linting.
- b) Build and publish a canary release to npm
- c) Measure the bundle size of the library
- d) Automatic releases on merge

This significantly improved the quality of each release, reduced amount of bugs, and overall developer experience

- Implemented a new Queries page with rich graphs and performant UI
- Implemented from scratch flame graph page using only React + CSS

Senior frontend engineer

Leroy Merlin

May 2019 - Dec 2021 (2 years 8 months)

Key results:

- New main page built using webcomponents.
- New header.
- Microfrontend architecture, template, tech stack, best practices, pipelines, recommendations, quality requirements made from scratch
- New product listing page built using new microfrontend approach (Lighthouse perf score > 90 at mobile).
- SSR time reduced to 40ms at 95 percentile
- Improved test coverage from 15% to 84%
- Performance testing as a part of microfrontend's pipeline

- As a lead maintainer in collaboration with designers made UI-kit
- Functional cross-browser testing using CodeceptJS(Playwright)
- Tech interviewing
- Mentoring



Middle/Senior frontend engineer

CASHOFF Russia

Jul 2017 - May 2019 (1 year 11 months)

Key results:

- Created all new webapp with a lot of data visualization and rich user interactions using react, kefir.js, d3 and typescript.
- made new theming system, time to create and support multiple (somewhere around 12) themes reduced by 50%.
- Leading team of four frontend engineers.
- Interviewing frontend engineers.
- In collaboration with designers introduced design system and ui-kit based on it.
- Significantly reduced number of problems with backend and automate local deployment using docker.



Full Stack Engineer

Yusto

Jul 2016 - Jul 2017 (1 year 1 month) Supporting and improving online stores. Writting delivery, payment service functionality Frontend optimizations LAMP server support

Education



Ivanovo State Power University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2012 - 2016

Skills

Testing • High Performance Web Sites • Redux • Apollo GraphQL • Microfrontends • WebComponents • React query • React.js • Design Systems • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)